<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://borker.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://borker.co/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-10-26T12:53:38-07:00</updated><id>http://borker.co/</id><title>Borker dot co</title><subtitle>home to the thoughts, writing and design of Ryan Borker</subtitle><entry><title>Lacelook</title><link href="http://borker.co/project-lace/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lacelook" /><published>2016-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://borker.co/project-lace</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://borker.co/project-lace/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;lace&quot;&gt;Lace&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently advise &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lacelook.com/&quot;&gt;Lace&lt;/a&gt; on their product and business strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lace helps fashion bloggers earn money by automatically tagging pictures they post on social media with similar clothing items they can by with affiliate links.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Lace" /><summary>A note about my involvement with Lace</summary></entry><entry><title>What changes should Snapchat make to its Discover feature that would significantly increase the product’s relevance as a news source?</title><link href="http://borker.co/snapchat-discover/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What changes should Snapchat make to its Discover feature that would significantly increase the product’s relevance as a news source?" /><published>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://borker.co/snapchat-discover</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://borker.co/snapchat-discover/">&lt;p&gt;Answer originally written on Quora, where it won a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-changes-should-Snapchat-make-to-its-Discover-feature-that-would-significantly-increase-the-product%E2%80%99s-relevance-as-a-news-source/answer/Ryan-Borker&quot;&gt;knowledge prize.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;theres-some-evidence-and-a-strong-hypothesis-that-snapchat-will-just-remove-the-discover-feature-however-some-ideas-for-keeping-the-discover-feature-relevant&quot;&gt;There’s some evidence and a strong hypothesis that Snapchat will just remove the Discover feature. However, some ideas for keeping the ‘Discover’ feature relevant:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use it for vertically focused e-commerce (specifically clothes, food, movies)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make it hyper local (eg what pokemon are around, funniest faces at the Yankees game)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn it into a snap version of Instagram explore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot at stake, since some major publishers (BuzzFeed, Cosmo) generate a significant portion of their traffic now through Snapchat. Cosmo generates as many views through Snapchat as it does on its main site. BuzzFeed gets 20% of its traffic. [1] Snapchat now has more users than Twitter by the way [2] .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-is-discover-now&quot;&gt;WHERE IS DISCOVER NOW?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s first look at the UI to see what clues we can draw from it. You can often understand where a feature is going if you look at where it is, and the changes the company has put into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the current Discover screen (8/30/16):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://borker.co/assets/img/sc-discover.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;A discovery!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the current Stories screen (8/30/16):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://borker.co/assets/img/sc-stories1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;A likely story!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice anything?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover stories have already migrated to the stories stream. The stories there focus on 2 use cases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Additional content: you already watched all of your friends’ snaps and you want more. Here’s some click-baity stuff for you to look at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) “Live”: live is ‘in’ right now. YouNow follows Facebook Live follows Periscope, etc. People love looking into other people’s more interesting experiences from the comfort of their own home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the same types of content you find on Discover page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quick-history-what-happened-to-discover&quot;&gt;QUICK HISTORY: WHAT HAPPENED TO DISCOVER?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://borker.co/assets/img/sc-discover2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Detective work&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover used to be the bubbles from publishers, putting their name out their first, but the new shift focuses even more on the individual piece of news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snapchat’s new update of Discover offers a subscribe button at the bottom of each piece, I suspect pushes the content to the top of your feed and also provides a metric that Snapchat can use to show brands how effective maintaining a Snapchat presence is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-you-even-need-discover&quot;&gt;DO YOU EVEN NEED DISCOVER?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover right now is a source of revenue for Snapchat: brands pay Snapchat a percentage of their ad revenues to remain on the page [3]. They can (or could at one point) also pay to take-over a publisher’s Discover channel, to the order of $50,000. [4] Not cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not everyone has seen value in Discover. Very high quality brands, like the NFL and the Onion, no longer seem to post on Discover, and some brands (eg Yahoo) have been kicked off the platform for not posting content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given how Snapchat is growing, it’s no surprise that Snapchat’s much bigger opportunity is providing ads in between Snaps, something that will generate $1B in revenue for them or more if they have it their way [5] . I suspect that makes the revenue generated by Discover seem like chump change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does matter to some brands though,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;future-of-discover&quot;&gt;FUTURE OF DISCOVER:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve written before that Snapchat has a great forum for short form news, because it captures attention very well, especially from young people (see: Is Snapchat really a good place to read and discover news?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover offers, at its core, a reason to stay on the platform after you’ve consumed all of your friends’ snaps. That’s important for Snapchat, whose sole business model is sucking up your attention and turning it into money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe Discover’s ‘platform’ based news delivery will eventually be phased out in favor of a ‘feed’ based delivery, similar to the way the stories and live tiles are being used now. Why? People ultimately don’t care about the publisher, just the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe Snapchat will ultimately phase out the Discover tab as an idea, but how could it make it more relevant to a news source, or as a product:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Discover for vertically focused e-commerce:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘But Ryan, commerce isn’t news.’ Sure it is. If Kylie’s hairstyle is news, the launch of a new product or a sale can be news. We don’t even need to argue on this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snapchat recently bought Vurb, and I suspect a large reason they did so was to build out Snapchat’s integrations across other apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea here would be that certain kinds of e-commerce lend themselves incredibly well to Snapchat’s platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Imagine fashion bloggers showing off their looks on Snapchat with a purchase link. You can only view it once and buy it, afterward it’s gone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Imagine a happy hour filter that could steer you to a nearby restaurant with cheap drink prices if you post to your story&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Imagine previews of movies on the platform that unlock a special filter you can use in your snaps (eg watch the trailer and unlock the Incredible Hulk filter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Totally doable, monetizable, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-discover-hyper-local&quot;&gt;Making Discover hyper-local:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They could change the core part of Discover to what’s happening around you right now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Super cute cat stuck in tree”
Watch Live: “Skateboarding in your local park”
Meet now: “Rare Pokemon at the convenience store”
This will be hard due to the amount of content required, but there’s certainly a possibility of making it happen, especially if they can find a way to reward users creating the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;instagram-explore-for-snapchat&quot;&gt;Instagram ‘Explore’ for Snapchat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The explore tab on Instagram has a similar reason for existing as the Discover tab: keep you engaged after you’ve gone through your feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snapchat could basically pull the same trick off: start ordering Snaps that you’d like from the past 7 days that you can only see through the discover tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since most news on Snapchat lasts 1 day, the ability to go further into the past could actually be a hook for people in the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;CONCLUSION:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover was an initial test by Snapchat to see how successful publishers would be on their platform. The test has gone well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Snapchat will now focus on between Snap ads, which will become their largest money maker—this opens up some more speculative uses for the Discover page and feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focus and deep attention provides some exciting possibilities for the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ibtimes.com/snapchat-discover-one-year-later-how-23-media-companies-are-building-stories-evan-2281851&quot;&gt;1 Snapchat Discover One Year Later: How 23 Media Companies Are Building Stories For Evan Spiegel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fipp.com/news/features/three-questions-publishers-have-about-snapchat-discover&quot;&gt;2 Three questions publishers have about Snapchat Discover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3] Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnbc.com/2016/02/18/snapchats-ad-rates-drop-as-brands-find-problems.html&quot;&gt;4 Snapchat’s ad rates drop as brands find problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adweek.com/news/technology/snapchat-launches-colossal-expansion-its-advertising-ushering-new-era-app-171924&quot;&gt;5 Snapchat Launches a Colossal Expansion of Its Advertising, Ushering in a New Era for the App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="design" /><summary>Still important, though</summary></entry><entry><title>‘People spend more time watching Netflix than reading, socializing and exercising - combined.’ Welcome to the Matrix</title><link href="http://borker.co/thought-4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="'People spend more time watching Netflix than reading, socializing and exercising - combined.' Welcome to the Matrix" /><published>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://borker.co/thought-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://borker.co/thought-4/">&lt;p&gt;You need something here, but you already got what you were looking for… I hope.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="thought" /><summary>food for thought</summary></entry><entry><title>Ever consider how most news articles now have tons of links, and you have no idea which are important or not?</title><link href="http://borker.co/thought-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ever consider how most news articles now have tons of links, and you have no idea which are important or not?" /><published>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://borker.co/thought-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://borker.co/thought-3/">&lt;p&gt;You need something here, but you already got what you were looking for… I hope.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="thought" /><summary>food for thought</summary></entry><entry><title>No product plan survives contact with the user</title><link href="http://borker.co/thought-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No product plan survives contact with the user" /><published>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://borker.co/thought-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://borker.co/thought-2/">&lt;p&gt;You need something here, but you already got what you were looking for… I hope.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="thought" /><summary>food for thought</summary></entry><entry><title>If you’re mean to people, do you end up bankrupt after a lawsuit with Hulk Hogan?</title><link href="http://borker.co/thought-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="If you're mean to people, do you end up bankrupt after a lawsuit with Hulk Hogan?" /><published>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://borker.co/thought-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://borker.co/thought-1/">&lt;p&gt;You need something here, but you already got what you were looking for… I hope.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="thought" /><summary>food for thought</summary></entry><entry><title>Shortlist</title><link href="http://borker.co/project-shortlist/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shortlist" /><published>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://borker.co/project-shortlist</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://borker.co/project-shortlist/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;shortlist&quot;&gt;Shortlist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cofounded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joinshortlist.com&quot;&gt;Shortlist&lt;/a&gt; where I am the COO and Head of Product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top finance companies have (including 7 of the top 30 asset managers) used Shortlist to recruit outstanding individuals to their most senior roles. These roles would otherwise have gone to retained search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shortlist platform achieved a number of industry firsts: 
- First to receive exclusivity on postings
- First to recruit at the senior level (C-suite, SVP, etc.)
- First vertical ‘curated’ network for senior level recruiting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FundFire, an industry leading publication for asset management, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fundfire.com/c/1243123/138313/managers_dial_tech_scour_senior_talent&quot;&gt;profiled us here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about Shortlist’s value to people who used it &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinshortlist.com/a/home/im/connector/about&quot;&gt;on the site&lt;/a&gt;, or you can learn more about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinshortlist.com/a/home/im/connector/platform&quot;&gt;platform itself&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Shortlist" /><summary>A note about my involvement with Shortlist</summary></entry><entry><title>My Writing</title><link href="http://borker.co/my-writing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Writing" /><published>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://borker.co/my-writing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://borker.co/my-writing/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing&quot;&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write often, though not nearly as much as I should. In my spare time, you’ll find me answering questions on tech news / trends, imagining the future, exploring social issues, and, of course, chronicling design ideas I like and dislike. Check out the sections below to see some of my more ‘popular writing.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quorahttpswwwquoracomprofileryan-borker&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/profile/Ryan-Borker&quot;&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write on Quora from time to time. In part because it pays better than a lot of other writing. Some of the popular things I’ve written are about running and tech strategy. Highlights include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;should-i-complete-a-marathon-without-traininghttpswwwquoracomis-it-possible-to-complete-a-marathon-without-training-for-it&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-complete-a-marathon-without-training-for-it&quot;&gt;Should I complete a marathon without training?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hint: no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-did-uber-beat-lyfthttpswwwquoracomwhy-was-uber-so-successful-vs-lyft-sidecar-etc&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Why-was-Uber-so-successful-vs-Lyft-Sidecar-etc&quot;&gt;Why did Uber beat Lyft?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one got published in Newsweek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-will-marketing-change-in-the-next-10-yearshttpswwwquoracomhow-is-marketing-going-to-evolve-over-the-next-ten-years-as-a-result-of-technological-innovation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/How-is-marketing-going-to-evolve-over-the-next-ten-years-as-a-result-of-technological-innovation&quot;&gt;How will marketing change in the next 10 years&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speculating on the future of marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;is-the-lobster-and-indictment-of-our-tinder-driven-dating-culturehttpswwwquoracomis-the-lobster-an-indictment-of-our-tinder-driven-dating-culture&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Is-The-Lobster-an-indictment-of-our-Tinder-driven-dating-culture&quot;&gt;Is the Lobster and indictment of our Tinder-driven dating culture?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do pop culture too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-can-we-improve-hiring-diversityhttpswwwquoracomwhat-are-specific-things-employers-can-do-today-to-build-more-diverse-technical-teams&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-are-specific-things-employers-can-do-today-to-build-more-diverse-technical-teams&quot;&gt;How can we improve hiring diversity?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent a lot of time thinking about this at Shortlist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mediumhttpswwwmediumcomborker&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:/www.medium.com/@borker&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Medium, I take a more speculative or reflective approach. Don’t expect miracles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;youre-better-off-dead-than-on-facebookhttpsmediumcomborkeryoure-better-off-dead-than-on-facebook-linkedin-or-twitter-d466806544d5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@borker/youre-better-off-dead-than-on-facebook-linkedin-or-twitter-d466806544d5&quot;&gt;You’re better off dead than on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of time thinking about how we spend our attention, and whether it’s intentional or not. Social media takes a huge share of our most precious resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-prepare-for-your-first-investor-meetinghttpsmediumcomlisten-to-my-storychecklist-how-to-prep-for-your-first-investor-meeting-c119c0fc74eb&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/listen-to-my-story/checklist-how-to-prep-for-your-first-investor-meeting-c119c0fc74eb&quot;&gt;How to prepare for your first investor meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Featured in Mattermark Daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;is-the-weak-tie-deadhttpsmediumcomjoinshortliststrong-ties-are-more-important-than-ever-bb2136d4dd1f&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@JoinShortlist/strong-ties-are-more-important-than-ever-bb2136d4dd1f&quot;&gt;Is the weak tie dead?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think weak ties are overemphasized. We need to begin to reform strong ties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-anyone-stop-linkedinhttpsmediumcomjoinshortlistcan-anyone-stop-linkedin-hints-from-the-users-911cd653ec23&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@JoinShortlist/can-anyone-stop-linkedin-hints-from-the-users-911cd653ec23&quot;&gt;Can anyone stop LinkedIn?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written from Shortlist’s perspective, before the acquisition. I still believe this.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="writing" /><category term="quora" /><category term="medium" /><category term="updates" /><category term="jekyll" /><summary>Read more about my writing.</summary></entry><entry><title>Design isn’t better, it’s just cheaper</title><link href="http://borker.co/design-cheap/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Design isn't better, it's just cheaper" /><published>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://borker.co/design-cheap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://borker.co/design-cheap/">&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://borker.co/assets/img/design-cheap.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Brought to you by cheap computing power and Adobe (tm)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a passing thought this morning: design has made it. We see an upsurge of visibly passionate digital designers, and an abundance designs that are, ostensibly, very good. Everyone’s stuff looks better, from furniture to webpages. Look at that crap they did in the 80s and 90s (and even early 2000s) with their software and their industrial lighting: how did they live with themselves?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn’t take me long to realize that I was, once again, fooled by my own perception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tend to pat ourselves on the back and think that we’ve had a ‘renaissance’ in design, that design is no longer considered an extra but vital to success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We, the powerful and vocal design community, brought this about!” we exclaim with glee. We believe we have vindicated the value of design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If only it were true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design-is-cheap&quot;&gt;Design is Cheap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hypothesis ended up with realizing that design is now cheap. We’ve enabled a myriad of development, design and fabrication frameworks that allow us to create, develop, and implement fantastic designs at a fraction of the cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a great disservice to any of the older designers to say that the ‘new’ generation is somehow better. I suspect industrial designers didn’t design those soulless corporate cafeterias because they wanted to destroy people’s lives. I suspect it was because other options were prohibitively expensive. Back then, 33 extra megahertz could soothe away any aesthetic issues with your PC; $5,000 office lights could make Philippe Starck the richest man on earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corporate profit is higher than it ever has been before. Design is cheaper than it ever has been before. Occam’s razor, the simplest explanation is often correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, everyone can now afford to look good, sit in good furniture, and have well designed apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Because of this economic affordability, design affordances can change for the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-now&quot;&gt;So what now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can understand now why digital design is more important than ever. Apple nailed that into the collective consciousness. Due to them and due to the tireless effort from designers everywhere, we now live in a fantastic golden age of design.
It’s our privilege to enjoy it, exploit it, and hopefully not screw it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, let’s at least agree that it’s (mostly) not our fault.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="design" /><summary>Still important, though</summary></entry><entry><title>Big Complaints of LinkedIn Users</title><link href="http://borker.co/linked-in/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Complaints of LinkedIn Users" /><published>2016-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://borker.co/linked-in</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://borker.co/linked-in/">&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://borker.co/assets/img/linked-in.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Please add me?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over a decade after LinkedIn started its growth to become the dominant professional network of choice, Jeff Weiner became introspective in the New Year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-has-linkedin-helped-you-achieve-your-professional-goals&quot;&gt;How has LinkedIn helped you achieve your professional goals?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He asked, soliciting feedback from the hundreds of millions of folks on LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feedback came streaming in: 700 people responded publicly to his request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post we explore the results, both good and bad. And point to hints at how enterprising upstarts could exploit this feedback and attempt to dethrone LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-overview-of-the-data&quot;&gt;An Overview of the data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;720 individuals posted 760 comments. The comments ranged from the sincere and basic to the oddball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These responses reinforce the obvious: LinkedIn is a fantastic tool, but not a perfect one. LinkedIn has succeeded in becoming most things to most people. However, some LinkedIn doubters highlighted some issues fundamental to the LinkedIn platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Statistically, most people were enthusiastic: about 70% of the posts were positive praise and stories. However, the remaining 30% provided mixed concerns and some negative stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the highlights below, with accompanying quotes from LinkedIn users who responded to Jeff’s question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-800lb-gorilla-in-a-great-looking-suit&quot;&gt;The 800lb Gorilla in a great-looking suit&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-linkedin-is-good-at-is-no-surprise&quot;&gt;What LinkedIn is good at is no surprise:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Helping people network and find people they otherwise wouldn’t have&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn is the world’s professional directory of record. “Bridging the gap” by finding mutual connections remains LinkedIn’s most powerful quality. Need a new freelance client? A connection will doubtless know someone. Need to reach a sales prospect? Same story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to understate how important and valuable this tool and ability is to people. Hundreds of comments mentioned it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;User Voice:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“LinkedIn is a great resource for developing professional knowledge, network and careers updates.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“But for LinkedIn, I never would have met one of my most trusted mentors, and I would have missed out on the career opportunity of a lifetime. Thanks, LI!”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“LinkedIn provided me with an active and engaging network, people I would never have met without this platform, whom I would never have dared to approach either”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“This site is perfect to reaching out across the world and communicate with other professional sharing the same passions through different backgrounds and cultures.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Sourcing Talent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for entry to mid-level white-collar talent, you can’t beat LinkedIn in most domains. There are exceptions (eg engineering, financial services), but for your next marketer, recruiter, accountant, or consultant, LinkedIn is without a doubt the place to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;User voice:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Jeff, my company leverages linked in to learn more about potential hires and source talent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Reconnecting and maintaining relationships&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staying in touch with people is hard — especially as you get older, your career progresses in different directions and your network grows larger. Students, as well as professionals young and old, find it a great way to reconnect. With the new features in the mobile app (card based reminders plus a new messaging client), it’s now even easier. It’s painless to send congrats and message people you haven’t seen in a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;User voice:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Thanks to LinkedIn I’ve been able to reconnect with those past colleagues and share new interests and ideas.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Career guidance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students and people young and old are having success figuring out what they want to do, by contacting folks and alumni they know. It’s a powerful way to figure out as a student what careers are available, what they’re like and whether they’re ultimately a fit for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;User voice:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“I have enjoyed LinkedIn, I began using an account as a sophomore in college, I didn’t know what career path to choose and it made me nervous since I was graduating early in just a year, I talked with Land-o-Lakes recruiters who were very helpful. I looked into project coordinating internships with purina and other feed sales training internships. LinkedIn has let me explore my options by talking with different recruiters and business men and women to figure out what I was interested in. Currently, I am a life style product specialist for Eaton Farm Bureau Coop in Charlotte, Mi. “&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Keeping up on industry news&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest successes LinkedIn has had in terms of engagement is becoming a content platform that matters. Beginning with the influencer program, LinkedIn has become a massive generator of original professional content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;User voice:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Pulse is reconnecting my writing muse back. I like LinkedIn just as I like Netflix- they both offer me freedom to choose what, whom, how and when to engage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Personal Branding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, people love looking at themselves and Linkedin has become an engaging way to showcase your career highlights. Plus, with Linkedin’s network analytics, users can discover how they rank compared to others in their industry and network: vanity sells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;User voice:
”It is invaluable for me. I have a huge contact list, have found a number of jobs, got my first Board position and ‘talk’ with the senior people in my industry. Today I hit number 1 in the ‘People Like Me’ section and the top 3% of my 4000 contacts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cracks-in-the-armor&quot;&gt;Cracks in the armor?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 30% minority was equally vocal about their concerns about the platform. Looking a bit closer, we can begin to see some of the limits of LinkedIn. Unfortunately, these limits may present fundamental problems in order for the platform to stay relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Too much ‘noise’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the increase in focus on content, people find it is becoming worryingly like Facebook. Many people like that they can catch news from the industry, but people find their feed noisy. Instead of seeing only job changes and professional news, they’re bombarded with inspirational quotes, quizzes and other bits of digital trivia. It feels irrelevant at best, distracting at worst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just yesterday, stalwart Silicon Valley veteran @JohnBattelle posted a plea for Medium not to ‘become LinkedIn Pulse.’ From experts to normal users, LinkedIn has begun to feel noisy to many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;User voice:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Looks more like Facebook… Both good and bad !”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Haven’t been using it very much lately because it’s becoming another Facebook. There are way too many people on here promoting things that don’t have anything to do with work or any kind of profession”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A large and impersonal network&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn is your network of everybody. People you met at a conference over a few cocktails; your coworkers; old classmates: all ‘Connections.’ But most people know that’s not how relationships work. Relationships live, they grow and die over time. Your best friend in college may not take your call so quickly 30 years later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s one issue people are finding with LinkedIn. It’s getting too big and diffuse to be meaningful, and feels increasingly less human. The story below about the work anniversary really hit home the problem I myself have found with LinkedIn. You can’t tell ‘genuine’ thoughts from mindless button-clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;User voice:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“I had an odd experience today with my 12th work anniversary notifications. I started replying to everyone for their well-wishes and realized that they are all form-fill type responses. It made me feel dirty and unwanted — haha — not really, but just seemed very depersonalized.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) “Drowned-out from great opportunities”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a network of everybody, everybody can contact everybody. Unfortunately this means that there are a lot of inappropriate requests mixed in with the valuable ones — the network is feeling more spam-y.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;User voice:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“The sales tools are not helpful if potential clients are bombarded with messages like mine.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Still a long way to go Jeff. I would love to be more connected with potential business projects in my field. Right now it’s too cluttered.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“I don’t think using LinkedIn makes it easier to find work. My experience with LinkedIn, 1 out of ten recruiters bother to respond back to emails.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Not relevant for senior folks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a follow-up post we’ll see that many senior-level folks have not created LinkedIn profiles. Why? Because of the issues highlighted above. CEO’s and decisions-makers don’t need to be on LinkedIn; many don’t want to be. And that’s a problem for aspiring leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;User voice:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“The single-biggest problem with LinkedIn is that it COULD be much more powerful and relevant than it is; a lot of decision-makers at companies, in large part because they’re decision-makers, don’t have time to be on here a lot.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-way-to-dethrone-linkedin&quot;&gt;A way to dethrone LinkedIn?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s clear LinkedIn is going nowhere. They consistently surprise on earnings and are a hugely well-run organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, no tool can be everything to everyone (even at their size) and, as a result, there are areas where LinkedIn is vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enterprising companies willing to go all-in and bet big on some of these weaker areas might, just might, be able to dethrone LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan
Founder and Head of Product, Shortlist
February 2016&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="design" /><summary>Still important, though</summary></entry></feed>
